Annie Jenkins Sallee papers, Inclusive: 1897-1967, undated, Bulk: 1897-1944
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Annie Jenkins Sallee papers
Inclusive: 1897-1967, undated, Bulk: 1897-1944
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
715
Sallee, Annie Jenkins
10 document boxes.
This collection includes original manuscripts, reports, photographs, newspaper clippings, scrapbooks, diaries, biographical documents, and letters collected and/or produced by Annie Jenkins Sallee, William Eugene Sallee, and associates.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Annie Jenkins Sallee was born on 1877 February 28 in Waco, Texas, the daughter of Judge Warwick Hoxey and Jessie Speight Jenkins. She received her B. S. degree with honors at Baylor University in 1897 and her master's degree from Baylor in 1899, being the first woman from Baylor to earn a master's degree. After teaching one year at Moody Bible Institute and two years at Decatur Baptist College, she attended the Baptist Missionary Training School in Chicago, graduating in 1905. This prepared her for her future career as a Southern Baptist Convention missionary to China.
While still in Texas Annie Jenkins met William Eugene Sallee, another missionary to China, whom she married on 1906 September 18 in China. Dr. Sallee was educated at Georgetown College and Rochester Theological Seminary. Dr. and Mrs. Sallee were both pioneers of the interior mission field in China, where Mrs. Sallee organized an "industrial school" for women. In 1930 they returned to the United States, when Dr. Sallee became home secretary of the Southern Baptist Foreign Missionary Board.
After her husband's death in 1931, Mrs. Sallee wrote his biography, Christ's Ambassador, which was followed by a biography of her father and a biography on the lives of missionaries in China. She returned to China in 1935 as a missionary to Kaifeng. During World War II, she was imprisoned by the Japanese for nine months. Returning to the United States in August 1943, she taught Sunday School at First Baptist Church of Waco, where she was a member. Annie Jenkins Sallee passed away on 1967 March 1.
Scope and Content
The Sallee papers include extensive family correspondence, diaries, photographs, newspaper clippings, and some biographical information on the Sallees. Although there are a few references to the Foreign Missionary Board and to friends in China, the majority of the collection relates to the Jenkins Family.
The most historically valuable series of the collection arguably come from the Literary Productions, Photographs, and Scrapbooks series. The Literary Productions series contains original manuscripts about the history of mission work in China, as well as the then current state of affairs in the Chinese political and cultural landscape. This series also contains biographical records on Annie Jenkins and William Eugene Sallee.
The Photographs and Scrapbooks series contain various pictures from different times and locations in Annie Jenkins Sallee's life, the most notable of these being of her mission work in China. Some scrapbooks have folders of loose pages accompanying them.
The bulk of the Diaries series was created by Annie Jenkins Sallee, with the rest of them coming from William Eugene Sallee.
The last series, Correspondence, contains a significant number of photocopied documents whose originals are not present in the collection.
Arrangement
Prior to current processing, the collection was housed in folders with titles. No dates were present on the folders. A prior finding aid was available.
Currently, the collection is arranged in five series: I. Literary Productions, II. Photographs, III. Scrapbooks, IV. Diaries, and V. Correspondence.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 715. Acquired 1974-06-12
Related Resources
Related references
Singleton, Hallie Jenkins. A glimpse into the Christ filled life of Annie Jenkins Sallee, missionary, 1905-1945. 1968.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Southern Baptist Convention -- History -- 20th century.; Southern Baptist Convention -- Missions -- China.; Southern Baptist Convention. Foreign Mission Board.
Subjects
Baptists -- Missions -- China.; Postcards.; Women and literature -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Women missionaries -- China.
Genres
Certificates.; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Diaries.; Manuscripts.; Newsletters.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Literary Productions, 1903-1967; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Excellent.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains literary work produced by Annie Jenkins Sallee as well as various collected materials and biographical information. This series is in excellent condition.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Postcards
  - Manuscript, Incomplete, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Literary Productions, General, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Literary Productions, Reports, circa 1920-1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Collected Materials, Newsletters, 1941 November - 1944 June (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Collected Materials, Newspaper Clippings, 1904-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Collected Materials, General, 1908-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Diaries, Excerpts From Diaries, circa 1897-1905 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Kaifeng Baptist School Announcement, 1924 June (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Translation From Kaifeng Daily News by William Eugene Sallee, 1912 November (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Biographical Records, William Eugene and Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1942-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Annie Sallee Memorial Book, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Collected Materials, Postcards, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Certificate and Clipping, 1903, 1911 (Box [1022], Folder 1)
- Photographs, 1897-1967; 2
  This series contains photographs from various times and locations in the United States and China. This series is in excellent condition.
  Photographic print
  - General, China Snapshots (1 of 4), circa 1907-1925 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - General China Snapshots (2 of 4), circa 1907-1925 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - General China Snapshots (3 of 4), circa 1907-1925 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - General China Snapshots (4 of 4), circa 1907-1925 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Portrait Photographs, circa 1897-1945 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Nature and Architecture, circa 1900-1950 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - China, 1907-1953, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Family and Friends (1 of 2), circa 1897-1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Family and Friends (2 of 2), circa 1897-1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - China, General, circa 1907-1925 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Cattle, circa 1907-1925 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - William Eugene and Annie Jenkins Sallee, circa 1897-1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Sallee Home in China, 1905-1960 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Family Snapshots, 1897-1940 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - William Eugene Sallee, 1897-1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1905-1960 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Scrapbooks, 1903-1950; 3
  General condition: Average.
  This series contains scrapbooks on various topics and span throughout most of Annie Jenkins Sallee's life. This series is in average condition.
  Photograph album; Photographic print
  - Scrapbook, First Year in China, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, First Year in China, loose materials, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, General, circa 1938-1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, General, loose materials, circa 1938-1950 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, Family Life 1, circa 1903-1959 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook, Family Life 1, loose materials, circa 1903-1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook, Family Life 2, circa 1915-1937 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook, Family Life 2, loose materials, circa 1915-1937 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Diaries, 1897-1909; 4
  Arrangement
  This series contains the diaries of Annie Jenkins and William Eugene Sallee. This series is in excellent condition.
  - Diary, Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1905-1910 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Diary, Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1911-1913 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Diary, Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Diary, Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Diary, Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Diary, Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1899 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Diary, Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1900 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Diary, William Eugene Sallee, 1905-1908 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Diary, Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1902-1905 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1901-1948; 5
  General condition: Good.
  This series contains correspondence from Annie Jenkins Sallee, William Eugene Sallee, extended family members, and the Baptist Foreign Mission Board. This series is in good condition.
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1906 February-August (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1906 September - 1907 June (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1907 July - 1908 June (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1908 July-November (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1908 December - 1909 June (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1909 June - 1910 May (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1910 May - 1914 February (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1914 March - 1916 February (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1916 February - 1917 April (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, May-August 1917 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1917 August - 1918 March (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1918 May - November (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1918 November - 1919 May (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1920 January (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1920 August - 1924 July (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1925 May - 1927 March (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1940 March - 1945 December (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Annie Jenkins and William Eugene Sallee, 1908 January - 1943 October (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1927 May - 1928 March (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, 1928 March - 1948 July (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Annie Jenkins and William Eugene Sallee, 1899-1906 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Annie Jenkins and William Eugene Sallee, 1916 April - 1920December (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Annie Jenkins and William Eugene Sallee, 1933 August - 1939 May (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Annie Jenkins and William Eugene Sallee, 1905 May -1928 September (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Annie Jenkins Sallee, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - William Eugene Sallee, 1928 September-December (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - William Eugene Sallee, 1928 December - 1929 January (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - William Eugene Sallee, 1929 January-February (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - William Eugene Sallee, 1929 February (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - William Eugene Sallee, 1929 February-March (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - William Eugene Sallee, 1929 March-April, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Dr. Love, 1916 August - 1921 August (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Dr. Buxton, 1934 February - 1938 September (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Dr. Madry, 1939 July - 1944 September (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Rankin, 1940 April - 1945 October (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Miss White, 1919 December - 1922 January (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Baptist Mission Board, 1904 January - 1905 December (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Baptist Mission Board, 1901 February - 1924 August (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Dr. Ray, 1921 April - 1933 August (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Dr. Ray, 1919 January - 1920 November (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Dr. Ray, 1913 December - 1918 August (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Dr. Willingham, 1903 April - 1909 October (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Dr. Willingham, 1910 February - 1911 December (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Dr. Willingham, 1912 February - 1914 July (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Brother Gwathney, 1911 August - 1913 February (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Porser, 1914 May - 1915 May (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Unknown, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - General, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Miss Ford, 1935 March - 1938 October (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - George W. and Josephine "Sittie" Jenkins Truett, 1911 May - 1942 March (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Gordon G. and Hale Harrison Jenkins Singleton, 1927 February - 1941 April (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Gordon G. and Hale Harrison Jenkins Singleton, 1941 May-December, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Jessie Speight Jenkins (Mrs. Warwick Hoxey), 1927 April - 1928 February, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - James "Jim" Robert Jenkins, 1908 August - 1928 April, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Warwick Hoxey Jenkins, 1912 September-1928 March, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Sarah Jenkins Graves Watts, 1927 February-1942 August (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - George Berry Graves, Jr., 1941 June-August (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Jenkins Family, 1927 February-1941 July (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Jenkins Family, 1941 August - December (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - William Eugene and Annie "Hannah" Jenkins Sallee, 1906 October-1929 August, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence (1 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence (2 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 14)